[Music]
hi guys and welcome back to my kitchen
so one of my favorite things to make are
gum paste flowers and I realized that it
had been a while since I'd added any to
the channel so for this week's video
tutorial I'm going to show you how to
make these really pretty Cosmos flowers
now these are perfect for a birthday
cake or a wedding cake or to incorporate
with other gaste flowers so let's get
started okay so the things that we're
going to need in order to make our
Cosmos flour is first of all I've got
some floral paste or some gum paste so
I've just got some different shades here
so you might want to make your flowers
in a light pink or I've got this Dusky
pink here I've also got a small amount
of yellow I've got my pme vea board now
if you don't have one of these is
absolutely fine I will just be using
this to roll out my petals but if you
don't have one I'll show you how to do
that also I've then got my foam Bal some
edible glue my rolling pins and my botle
some 24 gauge wire now this one I've
just cut into lengths of around 4 in
you'll need nine pieces of that for each
flower I've then also got a cosmos
flower petal cutter and my Squire's
petal veiner some tweezers and my metal
TOs and number two piping tip just of a
very small circle on the end some floral
tape and just some Stamm a variety of
different shades of petal dust along
with my paint brushes and lastly I've
just got a few spoons and also just a
little pot here where I've mixed just a
small amount of castor sugar and
granulated sugar okay so the first thing
that I'm going to work on are the petals
now the cosmos flowers have eight petals
and they're all exactly the same so I've
just got my vein in Bard here so as you
can see it's just got this groove cut
out so as we roll over it we'll get a
wider section to poke the wire into I've
also got my veiners and my petal cutter
along with some edible glue so I'm just
going to take a small amount of that gum
paste and just place that on top of one
of the Groves and then just going to
roll this out so it's as thin as I can
get it when I peel that back you can
just see that we've got this raised
triangle of gum paste now if you haven't
got one of these balls you can just do
this by hand so instead of rolling it on
the board I'm just going to use a small
rolling pin and just start to roll out
my gum paste now when my gum paste is
around 3 mm in thickness I'm just going
to roll down the sides leaving a
triangle in the center so just smooth
out the right side the left side and the
top and when we're finished as you can
see we're left with a raised area of the
gum paste which is almost identical to
how it's created on the board now the
only reason that I use the board is just
to make it slightly quicker I'm just
going to turn that over so you've got
the raised area on the top and just use
my cutter and cut out one of those
petals now to make this look more
realistic I'm just going to bring in my
foam mat and my botle and just run that
around the edges just to thin those out
but we want to stop before they start to
ruffle I'm then going to pick up one of
my wires and just run my fingers along
the end just just to create a slight
curve at the bottom pop the end of that
into some edible glue and just push that
wire into the raised gumpaste and then
just going to make sure the end of that
petal is stuck firmly to that piece of
wire I'm then going to bring in my ve
now now this one is just in two pieces
so I'm just going to line my Petal on
top and just push that Viner onto the
petal and when I take it off you can see
we've got this really pretty veined Lea
so all I'm going to do is just hold the
wire and just slightly bend on that and
I'm just going to bring in one of my
spoons and just lay that in the spoon to
dry so all this is doing is just
creating a slight upward curve so all
I'm going to do is make eight identical
ones of these okay so once I've created
all eight petals I'm just going to set
these to one side just until our gum
paste has hardened so the the next thing
I'm going to do is work on the center of
my flour okay so the first thing that
I'm going to do is take the pot of sugar
so this has a combination of Casta sugar
which is slightly finer and some
granulated sugar in there and I've also
got some of my Stam in now these are
double-ended and I just want to make
these look like they're covered in
pollen so I'm just going to take some of
my petal dust now I've just got an egg
yellow here and a prime Rose and I'm
just going to pop a small amount of
these into the sugar I'm just going to
shake that pot around so that that Sugar
gets completely covered and then just
going to use a paint brush and just
paint the end of my stamman in a
combination of two shades I'm just going
up about half a CM just because we will
be cutting these off I'm then just going
to make sure all the stam are lined up
and just dip the end of those into the
edible glue just so the tips of those
are covered and then just going to push
those into that pot of sugar and as you
can see the ends now look like they're
covered in pollen so I'm going to do
exactly the same to the other side I'm
then just going to pop these to one side
just to let that edible glue dry and for
the sugar to stick to the stam so I've
then just got a p sized amount of
gumpaste which I've colored in in this
yellow and I'm also going to take the
last of my wires so with my wire tools
I'm just going to create a loop at the
end and this is just going to allow the
wire to grip onto our gum paste so I'm
just going to roll the gum paste into a
teardrop shape and then going to pop the
end of that wire into some edible glue
and just push that into the end and then
just going to roll that gum paste onto
the length of wire so that I know that
it's stuck and just pull off any excess
I'm just going to push that onto the
surface just to make that top end flat
and then just going to take a piping tip
now this is the number two piping tip
just with a tiny Circle end and I'm just
going to push this into the end of that
gum paste creating small dents now once
that's completely covered I'm just going
to take some tweezers and I'm just going
to go in and pinch parts of that gum
paste just pulling it out just to give
it some texture and then just going to
bring back in that yellow petal dust and
just brush that all over the top I'm
then just going to bring back in those
stams that we created and just by using
some scissors I'm just going to cut off
the length of those and then just going
to pop a piece of that edible glue just
onto my plate and just using my tweezers
I'm just going to pick up the staming
and just pop the end into some edible
glue and then just going to push this
into the edge of my flower center and
all I'm going to do is just go around
the edge just creating a ring of those
stamman so as you can see we've just got
this outer ring on the edge and you can
see all that Sugar that's looking like
pollen I've then just taken a really
small amount of foliage green petal dust
and a very tiny paintbrush and I'm just
going to go in and just on the bottom of
some of those stayon and also just brush
it on some of those raised Parts there
we have the center of our flower okay so
here I've got my eight petals and they
have all dried and I've also just got a
plate here which I've just put some
petal dust on so I've just got some
Dusky pink some rose pink and a small
amount of violet now the cosmos flowers
come in all different col colors but all
I want to do is just have these ones
slightly darker at the center and just
go in a little bit lighter so I'm just
going to dust some of that Dusky Pink
Just onto the ends and then just bring
some of that Rose and the Violet in the
center so I'm going to do this to all of
my
petals okay so now all my petals have
been colored all I want to do is just
get my wires in the right place so we've
got the wire coming down here but where
it ends at the bottom of my petal all I
want to do is just bend that back at a
90° angle and then going to bring back
in the center of my flower and just
place my first petal up against it so
because of the shape that we made the
center The Petal is just going to sit
underneath and just come up from the
middle so for the next one I'm just
going to hold this in place and just pop
this underneath the first one and then
going to do exactly the same and just
work my way around and I'm just going to
pop the last one in that Gap there now
I'm going to make sure that all the
petals are pulled right the way up to
the top so I'm just going to take my
green floral tape now just to stick this
I'm just going to pop a small amount of
water just on the end of my fingers and
just put that on the end I'm then going
to pull out that floor tape and this is
just going to activate the gar and just
make it stick to itself and just start
winding it around and then just work my
way down the length of that wire and
once I get to the bottom I'm just going
to tear that tape off now some of these
may have moved slightly as we were
winding the wire so I'm just going to
move these what we're trying to do is
just keep the petals quite flat but also
curved up at the end which was why we
dried them in the spoons so once your
petals are evenly spaced out and you're
happy with how they look here we have
our finished cosmos flower I've got the
darker pink which I made in this video
and I've also got some examples of a
lighter pink with a Dusky pink Center
plus a brighter pink with a fuchsia pink
center now I've just teamed these with
some filler flower buds and I'll put a
link in the description below if you
want to also see how to make these I've
also got a variety of different gumpaste
flower tutorials on my channel so if
there's some other flowers you want to
see how to make then don't forget to
check those out I really hope you've
enjoyed this video and we'll find it
useful if you want to make your own
Cosmos flowers if you have then don't
forget to give this video a like and if
you'd like to see more videos like this
then don't forget to subscribe to the
channel you can also hit the
notification Bell next to the Subscribe
button and this will just alert you
every time a new video is uploaded so
until next time bye
[Music]